# **Eduardo Godoy**

## Software Engineer

□ +56 9 89573321 @ eduardo.gl@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/godoyeduardo ♀ github.com/EdGoll

i DNI: 15.557.610-3 i chilean i 39 years old ♀ Jorge Kenrick #989-55, Valparaíso, Chile



# **Summary**

Computer Engineer coding enthusiast and in constantly new learning and technologies adoptions, with extensive experience in the design and implementations of digital products in vast and middle scale. Currently, I have the role of Senior Software Architect, I also do teaching work allowing to deliver my knowledge and experiences to future professionals. I consider myself a person who watches over good relationships personally, is trained to deliver knowledge, is proactive, and is always available to support my coworkers.



## Work Experience

### 2021 - currently

### Application Architect, Liberty Mutual Insurance, Andes Region.

- > Architecting high volume web systems and large transaction client-server systems using serverless and/or containers architecture.
- > PoCs Implementation to coordinate solutions or facilitate evaluation as necessary.
- > Technical Lead and product owner in architecting and software development projects, constantly supporting and delivering knowledge to teams.
- > FullStack and coding enthusiast with JS, REST services, and Microservices.
- > Training and continuous help to developers in the knowledge of technology and resolution of coding problems.
- > Roadmap management of architecture projects.

AWS Java python Spring framework git React microservices serverless containers

### 2021 - currently

#### Support Researcher (part time), Universidad de Valparaíso, Fondef MAMAI

- > Implementation of techniques for natural language processing. (NLP).
- Research and implementation of NER and text generators models based on deep learning and transformers models.

Deep Learning | BERT | GPT-2 | python 3.9 | spaCy 3.0 | pytorch | keras | tensorflow | scikit learn | AWS Sagemaker

#### 2016 - 2021

#### Software Architect, Nationals Customs Service, Government of Chile.

- > Migration project to the public cloud using serverless and container architectures.
- > Design and implementation of rest APIs as part of an event-driven architecture.
- > Definition of strategy for efficient migration of applications to the cloud.
- > Design of architectures for the development of projects of the government of Chile.
- > Definition of architectural guidelines and building blocks for support software development projects.
- > Implementation of archetypes of applications, services, and processes for agile development.
- > Training and continuous help to developers in the knowledge of technology and resolution of coding problems.
- > Portfolio management of architecture projects.

AWS Java Apache Camel Spring framework git Angular REST OpenShift JBoss EAP microservices containers Kubernetes

#### 2012 - 2016

## Software Architect, Emergya, Consulting.

- > Design and implementation of archetype for software development.
- > Implementation of component architectures.
- > JBoss ESB-based Components Implementation.
- > Research and adoption of new technologies for continuous improvement of development processes.
- > Technical support to areas of development and operations in projects and contingencies.
- > Definition of architectural guidelines and standards for project and component development.
- > Execution of code audits for projects in development stage.

JBoss EAP JBoss SOA-P JSF RichFaces Eclipse IDE Hibernate Alfresco

### 2010 - 2012 | Software engineer, Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile.

- > Technical leader of projects in the area of education, using Java J2EE technology with ICEfaces and EJB frameworks.
- > Design and implementation of high availability production environment.
- > Design and implementation of student portal.
- > Design and implementation of base architecture for new development projects.

Glassfish Ms Sql Server Java iceFaces MyBatis

#### 2009 - 2010 | Software engineer Java, Tecnova, Chile

- > Project development for Java and Php telecommunications industry.
- > Evolutionary maintenance project for a life insurance company operations platform.
- > Geolocation project to record bandwidth measurements of BAM plans.
- > Development of measurement query application for help desk platform.
- > Design and implementation of a web application to record the activities of insurance agents using

Eclipse Java JSP JSF ADFfaces Oracle Php jquery Visual Basic

#### 2008 - 2009

### Data integration consultant, Power Data, Chile

- > Implementation of ETL processes in the Retail industry client.
- > Design and implementation of ETL process for mapping transactions from Cobol to relational data-

PowerCenter Cobol DB2 TeraData

#### 2008

#### Developer, DyBox, Chile

> Support for Java JEE application development.

ADFfaces EJB 2.1 TopLink OC4J.



## Teaching

#### 2010-2019

University teacher, subjects related to software design and programming for careers in the area of computer science, part time.

- > Universidad de Valparaíso Faculty of Engineering.
- > Universidad de Viña del Mar School of Technology.

## Education

- **Diploma Cloud Computing Architecture** Kibernum Academy, Chile 2021
- 2020 PhD Candidate - Computer engineering (in progress) - Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile
- Computer Engineering Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile
- Degree in Computer Science Universidad de Valparaíso, Chile 2009

## Certifications.

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner AWS, ID GF1B73BDEB1QQY39
- Analyst developer of software applications (TIC-PROG) 2018 ISFIA, ID a02785f4-7a11-4f20-9f29-890b52299a08
- 2014 ITIL v3 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management EXIN, ID 5158119.20318946

# **Competencies**.

Programming languages: Java, Python, Php, JS, C, DotNet-Core, ATEX.

Cloud Technologies: AWS, Azure, Containers, Kubernetes, OpenShift.

Frameworks: Spring Framework, camel, Angular, React, Hibernate, MyBatis, JSF (Primefaces, RichFa-

ces, iceFaces),

Data Base: Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Ms SQL Server

**Development Tools: Eclipse**, NetBeans, IntelliJ Idea, Maven, Ant, git, SVN

Middleware: JBoss EAP, JBoss SOA-P, Fuse, Tomcat, Glassfish

**Software design tools:** UML, Archi, Enterprise Architect.

**Machine learning tools:** python **sklearn**, **Keras, tensor flow**, Textblob, sapCy.

CI/CD tools: Jenkins, Sonar, Jmeter, Talend, Power Center.

Others skills: Clean code, Refactoring and Design and Enterprise Intergration Patterns.

# Training courses

2021 Cloud Practiotioner Essential Day. AWS

2021 Dev on agnostic cloud. Data Activa

2020 Application Development II: Implementing Microservice Architectures (DO283). Red Hat

2020 Application Development I: Programming in Java EE (AD183). Red Hat

2020 Introduction to Openshift Applications I (DO101). Red Hat

2018 Jboss Fuse - camel (JB421). Red Hat

2018 Jboss Enterprise Application Development (JB225). Red Hat

2017 Jboss Enterprise Application Development II (JB325). Red Hat

2016 Jboss Development with Hibernate Technology (JB297). Red Hat

2016 Jboss Enterprise Application Development (JB225). Red Hat

2015 Collaborative skills for the change (couching). LW Capacitaciones

2014 ITIL v3 Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management. Axelos

# Languages



Guillermo Farias, Manager of Departament of services IT

National customs services.

**1** +56 9 84492402

@ gfarias@aduana.cl

Cristian Villatoro, CEO

datamapit.

**1** +56 9 95162719

© cristian.villatoro@datamapit.cl